It’s like they just can’t sleep lately.
No physical issues present.
To get good sleep,
you need a healthy level of exercise...
Oh, and drinking some hot milk
to relax before bed can help, as well.
One, two! One, two!
Healthy level of exercise!
Hot milk to relax!
Now, let’s get to sleep.
Good night!
Ready, set, and... GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Put our palms together, raise them high, and let our lights unite
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
In rain, gales, or even blizzards
We can laugh together as friends
All of the gaps in the Index
let’s fill them in bit by bit
If you’re trying to be someone else
Don’t think like that
You’re fine just as you are
Don’t lose yourself
Recollect on what’s in your pocket
This is what makes us strong
A heartfelt bond that will never fade
Ready, set, and...
GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Let’s fly, higher and higher!
It’s fine to make mistakes
just rest your wings
When you’ve caught your breath
you can fly off once more!
Come along with us, oh-oh
Voltteccers
Pass the endlessly turning seasons,
and venture into brand-new skies
Wanival and Dekanuchan,
the Great Sleep Operation!
Wanival and Dekanuchan
couldn’t sleep again today?
Yeah...
What about Surfugo?
Out like a light.
They all do the same things, eat the same stuff,
and sleep in the same place,
so why can’t they seem to sleep...?
That is intriguing. Pokémon that are unable to sleep,
in the same conditions as those that can.
Wanival and Dekanuchan...
They’re not nocturnal Pokémon,
yet they’re unable to sleep.
There has to be some reason behind it.
Who’re you, old dude?
Ult, don’t be rude!
Whoops. I hadn’t introduced myself.
My name’s Neroli.
I study Pokémon sleep.
Study sleep?
Don’t tell me...
You’re the Professor Neroli
who studies Pokémon sleep ecology?
Yeah!
Pokémon sleep economy?
Many Pokémon feel better
after some good sleep,
and wake up prepared
to fully exert themselves.
Sleeping is very important!
Feeling better after
some good sleep...
Whoops. I’ll miss my ship
if I dilly-dally too much.
Are you going somewhere?
I do fieldwork on Wakakusa Isle.
Professor Neroli!
Could you see
my Wanival and Dekanuchan?
We can take you to Wakakusa Isle!
Huh?!
Next stop, Wakakusa Isle!
All done!
All done with what?
This is my room.
I put in surveillance cameras.
I told Wanival and Dekanuchan
to take a nap,
but it looks like
they still can’t sleep.
What are they like by nature?
Wanival is a kind and cheerful
little guy who loves to dance.
He’s serious,
with a little bit of a sensitive side.
Dekanuchan is daring and intense,
but she also has an artisan’s mindset,
and when she sets her mind on something,
she tends to lose track of all else...
Perhaps...
They could be afraid of something.
Huh?
Take a look. Dekanuchan is putting
quite a bit of force into her grip on her hammer.
You’re right!
Maybe their defensive instincts are kicking in,
to try and protect them from something.
Has anything been scaring them lately?
Scaring...?
Oh! “Here’s Ghosty From the Gaps”!
“Here’s Ghosty”...?
The heck’s that?
A type of ghost story stream
that’s taken off lately.
Though it’s all just
Ghost-type Pokémon popping out of gaps.
Everyone, thanks for tuning in.
Tonight, I wonder...
Which gap will the “Here’s Ghosty” come from?
Well, let’s get straight to it...
Isn’t that gap by the cabinet
kinda sketchy?
Woo... Where’s it gonna come from?
Ooh, so scary, so scary...
Ahh! Ah! Here’s Ghosty!
I was right!
Come on, I hear you, I hear you, I hear you...
What is it, what is that sound? So scary, scary...
Ahh! Here’s Ghosty!
No way! A Jupetta was back there?!
I found it fun,
to me it was like a video game.
But... Maybe it really scared
Wanival and Dekanuchan...
So I’m the one who
stopped you from sleeping...
Sorry, Wanival, Dekanuchan...
Dot...
I’ve an idea!
Why don’t you all come join me
on my fieldwork?
Huh?
The Kabigon at my destination
of Wakakusa Isle...
...produce a mysterious energy called “Drowsy Power”
that makes Pokémon drift off to sleep.
It’s bound to put Wanival
and Dekanuchan to sleep as well.
Amazing! Look!
What Pokémon is that?!
Ahh! And more over there!
Look, look!
Wow! And even here, too!
Shut it, Navi!
Those are Purin.
And that’s a Mankey.
It feels like the Pokémon here
are all super relaxed.
Even Wanival and Dekanuchan
should be able to sleep here, yeah?
They’re all riled up
because they’re in a new place...
Professor Neroli?
Take a look.
Ooh, a Kabigon! It’s mega-huge!
Shh.
Quiet, Ult!
Ahh, Metamon!
Don’t worry.
Kabigon’s belly is a safe place for Pokémon.
Wow...
I’m so jealous...
They’re all relaxing...!
It’s even making me feel mellower.
They’re getting sleepy?
Aww, they looked so close
to falling asleep!
I wonder why Kabigon got up.
It looks like it’s hungry.
Kabigon love to sleep,
but they also really love to eat.
I have an idea!
How about we make this?
“Hyper Sleep Butter Curry”?
A Kabigon favorite!
When they stuff their face
and belly with this,
they drift straight off.
Even the name’s
got me feeling sleepy!
We’re really good at making curry!
Yeah! You can leave it to us!
Roy, your curries are crazy spicy!
You’ll just wake it up!
Don’t worry.
The Hyper Sleep Butter Curry isn’t spicy.
Yay! I love curry!
Let’s all make it together!
Kabigon eat a staggering amount,
so it’ll be quite a taxing job...
Then, to make sure
Wanival and Dekanuchan nod off...
I’ll make it a huge helping
of Hyper Sleep Butter Curry!
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
The Hyper Sleep Butter Curry’s
ingredients are...
Calming Potatoes...
Relax Cocoa...
Restful Tomatoes...
...and Moomoo Milk.
Where do we get those?
And we need loads of ‘em, right?
You can have these guys help you;
they know this isle well!
Wow!
Nice to meet you!
Let’s split up
and gather the ingredients!
Masquernya,
let’s give it our best shot!
Wow! These are Calming Potatoes?
Masquernya!
Ready, and...
We picked ‘em!
Ooh, that’s a big one!
Huh?
Wanival.
You rest here.
You’re exhausted
from lack of sleep, right?
Keep an eye on the fruits
I picked with Dekanuchan.
Wanival! Dekanuchan!
Are you okay?!
Whoa! A Jupetta and a Ghost?!
Phew, so it was just
Restful Tomatoes...
Either way,
that’s a heck of an appetite.
It’s okay, Wanival, Dekanuchan.
Jupetta and Ghost are just hungry,
and they’re not scaring anyone, so you can relax.
Cap! It’s okay!
Give those to Jupetta and Ghost.
Everyone’s waiting, so let’s go.
We managed to get
all the ingredients!
Ooh! You sure gathered a lot.
Everyone, thanks for helping us out!
I’m seriously starvin’!
All right, time to make a Rising Voltteccers-style
Hyper Sleep Butter Curry!
Yeah!
Loudbone! Go ahead!
Whoa!
What?
You’re giving them back?
Maybe... they want to
get in on making it?
What should we do?
Yeah. Let’s have Jupetta
and Ghost help, too.
That just leaves Relax Cocoa
for the secret flavor.
Oh, thank you, Jupetta!
O-Oh...
Smells great!
Here!
What’re those?
You can use these fans
to adjust the heat.
Hilarious!
Navi wanna try!
Seems like Wanival and Dekanuchan
are all right now.
Gotta be almost ready, don’t it?
Nuh-uh! We still need to add
the most important ingredient!
Right, Dot?
Huh?
Come on, what’s the most important
part of making a curry?
Oh...
What, what is it? Tell Navi!
What every curry needs!
Which is...
...your heart!
Huh...?
Like this? Heart!
Yep!
Is this it? Heart!
Okay! Now you, Ult!
Like I’d ever do that! Right, Dot?
Let’s do it together.
Huh?!
I know painfully well
where you’re coming from...
But heart is an essential part of curry!
Huh?
Yeah, yeah!
Don’t worry. Heart isn’t scary!
We need your heart, Ult!
Here goes!
Ready, and...!
Rargh... Whatever!
Heart!
Kabigon.
This is Hyper Sleep Butter Curry. Dig in!
Seems like it’s a hit.
Thank goodness...
We should have some, too!
Yeah!
Time to dig in!
The curry I made tastes great!
Good, huh?
Meals always taste best
with everyone gathered ‘round.
Yeah.
Doesn’t Kabigon look
bigger than before?
Looks full and satisfied.
Now it might have a good sleep.
I’m stuffed and sweepy...
Been up and about
since morning, after all.
Wanival... Dekanuchan...
Good night.
Professor Neroli,
what are you doing?
Shh.
This is sleep research.
Sleep research?
That’s Purin’s Spacey Sleep.
It looks like it’s spacing out,
but it’s really just sleeping.
It looks like it’s awake!
And that’s Wooper’s Grinning Sleep,
where it smiles in its sleep.
That looks kinda fun!
That’s Mankey’s Angry Sleep.
It’s sleeping while angry.
I’m surprised it can sleep like that...
That’s Usokki’s Fake Tree Sleep,
where it acts like a tree while asleep.
Huh? Those two Togekiss
are each sleeping in different ways!
That’s Free-Flight Sleep.
And that one’s Acrobatic-Flight Sleep.
You can find various sleeping styles,
even among the same Pokémon.
There’s a Munna over there!
That’s Dream Smoke Sleep.
When Munna eat fun dreams,
they breathe out pink smoke.
I guess everyone
must be having fun dreams.
Oh, look!
Ult’s doing a Synchronized-With-Yamirami Sleep!
Navi’s doing a Metamon-Hugging Sleep
while it’s turned to stone!
Wh-What’s that?!
Ah... Cap sleeps like that often.
I-I’ve never seen anything like this!
A Pikachu’s Tail-Stand Sleep!
Shh!
Incredible!
Incredible, incredible, incredible!
It’s so incredible...
I’m gonna have
good dreams tonight!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Friede here!
It’s time to Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie!
Today’s topic is Kabigon!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Kabigon
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Sleeping Pokémon
Normal
Immunity
Thick Fat
Not much can wake
a Kabigon once it falls asleep,
but there’s an ace in the hole that can!
Do you know what it is?
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
See the answer after the commercials!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Gonna give my motivation button a little tap!
The power of hard work is amazing!
(Ahem!)
But if I slack off I might end up devolving...
Well, that’s no good!
But now you mention it...
I know button mashing won’t help at all
So stop shaking this maiden’s heart already
(Stop it!)
Getting attached, but then they turn away
When things just don’t go the way that you want...
Isn’t it so fun? Doesn’t it make your heart race?
Doesn’t it make you all excited?
When I feel a spark...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
Face to face with the dream I’ve always imagined...
I’ve got electric jolts running through me!
I’m so lovey-dovey I can’t even move!
When I know change is still inside of me...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
then we can be together forever
We’ll conquer any obstacle!
I know our future will shine!
So let’s be friends!
Pick up you! I want you! Hit chu straight in the heart!
Pick up you! I want you! We’re right at the peak of our adven-chu!!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Time to announce
the correct answer!
The answer is...
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
Startle it
Tickle it
Play a Flute
C: Play a Flute!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
A Pokémon Flute can apparently prompt
even a Kabigon to suddenly spring awake!
We can’t get through like this...
Don’t worry.
A Pokémon Flute!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
So, without further ado...
Next episode
Hey, hey, you heard of
Pokémon Contests?
What’s that? Some kinda battle?!
More like... a sparkling stage where you
vie to dazzle with your Pokémon’s charms!
Next episode
They’re super cool...
...and crazy cute!
Plus, they bring on the feels!
Whaddaya mean “feels”...?
And we’re going to enter
a Pokémon Contest for the first time!
Next episode
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Crazy Feels! This Is a Pokémon Contest, Dearie!!
“Dearie”?!
Tell me already,
what’s this “feels” thing?!